Section 2
Good morning, my name is Erica Matthews and I'm the owner of Matthews Island
Holidays, a company set up by my parents.
Thank you for coming to this presentation, in which I hope to interest you
in what we have to offer.
We're a small family-run company,
and we believe in the importance of the personal touch,
so we don't aim to compete with other companies on the number of customers.
What we do is build on our many years' experience more than almost any
other rail holiday company to ensure we provide perfect holidays
and a small number of destinations which we've got to know extremely well.
I'll start with our 6-day Isle of Man holiday.
This is a fascinating island in the Irish sea, with Wales to the south,
England to the east, Scotland to the north,
and Northern Ireland to the west.
Our holiday starts in Hashim, where your tour manager will meet you, then you'll
travel by ferry to the Isle of Man.
Some people prefer to fly from Luton instead and another popular option is to go by train to Liverpool
and take a ferry from there.
You have 5 nights in the hotel and the price covers 5 breakfast
and dinners and lunch on the 3 days when there are organized trips.
Day 4 is free and most people have lunch in a cafe
or restaurant in Douglas.
The price of the holiday includes the ferry to the Isle of Man, all
travel on the island, the hotel and the meals I've mentioned.
Incidentally, we tried to make booking our holidays as simple and fair as possible.
So, unlike with many companies, the price is the same whether you book six months in advance
or at the last minute.
And there's no supplement for single rooms in hotels.
If you make a booking, then need to change the start date, for example
because of illness.
You're welcome to change to an alternative date to a different tour for a
small administrative fee.
Okay,
so what does the holiday consist of?
Well on Day 1, you'll arrive in time for a short introduction by your
tour manager, followed by dinner in the hotel.
The dining room looks out at the river close to where it flows into
the harbour,
and there's usually plenty of activity going on.
On Day 2, you'll take the coach to the small town of peel, on
the way calling in at the Tynwald Exhibition.
The Isle of Man isn't part of the United Kingdom,
and it has its own parliament called Tynwald.
It's claimed that this is the world's oldest parliament that still functioning
and that it dates back to 979.
However, the earliest surviving reference to it is from 1422.
So perhaps it isn't quite as old as it claims.
Day 3, we have a trip to the Mountain Snaefell.
This begins with a leisurely ride along the promenade in Douglas in a horse-drawn
tram.
Then you board an electric train which takes you to the fishing village of
Laxey.
From there it's an 8km ride in the Snaefell Mountain railway to the top.
Lunch will be in a cafe giving you spectacular views of the island.
Day 4 is free for you to explore, using the pass which will give
you,
so you won't have to pay for travel on local transport
or for entrance to the island's heritage sites.
Or you might just want to take it easy in Douglas
and perhaps do a little light shopping.
The last full day, Day 5 is for some people.
The highlight of the holiday was a ride on the steam railway from Douglas
to port Erin.
After some time to explore, a coach will take you to the headland that
overlooks the Calf of Man, a small island just off the coast.
From there, you continue to castle town which used to be the capital of the Isle of Man
and its medieval castle.
And on Day 6, it's back to the ferry or the airport if you flew to the island
and time to go home.
Now I'd like to tell you a bit more...
(fade out)